<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>digital. [nomad]</title>
    <link>http://anthonymcook.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on digital. [nomad]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://anthonymcook.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>powerline</title>
      <link>http://anthonymcook.com/the-new-powerline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://anthonymcook.com/the-new-powerline/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;aside&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This post is modified from the original. Mostly readability improvements and changes necessitated by the new layout and backend engine. It has not been updated for the latest Powerline as I have long since switched to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bling/vim-airline&#34;&gt;Airline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While tweaking my configs, including fleshing out my .tmux.config and fixing bugs in my .vimrc I ran an update on my vim plugins. That&amp;rsquo;s when I noticed something was horribly wrong. Powerline wasn&amp;rsquo;t working anymore. It was throwing an error about Python. Python? What the hell? I don&amp;rsquo;t remember it requiring Python&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I discovered that it&amp;rsquo;d been completely rewritten and a lot had changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s clearly still Alpha quality software, so it will (probably) improve rapidly, but in the meantime there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of hurdles to jump through in order to get it even sort of working. Maybe I can save you a little time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-basics:b588c49916508cfd3540e7ace30ddadd&#34;&gt;The Basics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Powerline is useless without the below prerequisites, so make sure you install whichever ones you intend on using if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, but there&amp;rsquo;s a few caveats you want to watch out for before you even really get to the point of making use of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;utf-8-terminal-emulator:b588c49916508cfd3540e7ace30ddadd&#34;&gt;UTF-8 Terminal Emulator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay let&amp;rsquo;s face it, if you&amp;rsquo;re on OSX, iTerm2 is amazing and you should be using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s been some fixes to custom codepoint font support in iTerm in the last couple of weeks so its best if you grab a nightly or compile it yourself if you&amp;rsquo;re feeling really masochistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend downloading a precompiled nightly until a new stable is released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Latest stable should have full support.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install it as usual, it probably won&amp;rsquo;t explode. But if it does, wait until the next iTerm nightly or grab an official release and mourn your utf symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re on Linux then iTerm isn&amp;rsquo;t an option (sadly), so install rxvt-unicode or terminator or whatever you want, just make sure it has solid utf support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vim:b588c49916508cfd3540e7ace30ddadd&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vim needs to be compiled Python support, if you&amp;rsquo;re on OSX then MacVim has you covered already. You can install it with Homebrew and you&amp;rsquo;re good to go. On Linux you&amp;rsquo;ll have to select a package that supports it or compile it yourself. For instance Ubuntu I use &lt;code&gt;vim-nox&lt;/code&gt; for non-gui and &lt;code&gt;vim-gtk&lt;/code&gt; for gui support. The latter has better color support and since only has a library overhead of about 30MB it might be worth it to you to install anyway. If you&amp;rsquo;re on Gentoo make sure your USE flags have &lt;code&gt;+python&lt;/code&gt; in the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;python-and-the-powerline-module:b588c49916508cfd3540e7ace30ddadd&#34;&gt;Python (and the Powerline module)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need some sort of Python 2.7ish install (as far as I can tell), and you&amp;rsquo;ll need pip installed as well. The version that comes with Homebrew is good, but you&amp;rsquo;ll have to add a configuration option to your .vimrc if you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First install pip if you don&amp;rsquo;t have it already, and then you can install the Python module:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;$ pip install https://github.com/Lokaltog/powerline/tarball/develop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t even try to pip install powerline, the &amp;ldquo;powerline&amp;rdquo; package has nothing even slightly to do with this, its an unfortunate naming conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that was done I had to add this to my &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt; to get it to work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;python import sys; sys.path.append(&amp;quot;/usr/local/lib/python2.7/site-packages/&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But on OSX you might find the package here instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;python import sys; sys.path.append(&amp;quot;/Library/Python/2.7/site-packages&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-python-s-site-packages:b588c49916508cfd3540e7ace30ddadd&#34;&gt;Finding Python&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;site-packages&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your path might need to be different, if you can&amp;rsquo;t intuit it, you can have Python tell you where it hides its packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;First ensure that Python can find it by seeing if &lt;code&gt;powerline&lt;/code&gt; in the list of modules pip is aware of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;$ pip freeze | grep powerline
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If its there then you can open up a python repl and have it tell you where the file is at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import powerline
powerline.__file__
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have that, you can figure out the path to the site-packages directory that you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fonts:b588c49916508cfd3540e7ace30ddadd&#34;&gt;Fonts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of Powerline&amp;rsquo;s aesthetic appeal comes partly from its custom UTF fonts. So you&amp;rsquo;ll need those to get it looking its best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The codepoints have changed in the new version of Powerline. This means that &lt;strong&gt;your old fonts WILL NOT WORK&lt;/strong&gt;. Seriously, don&amp;rsquo;t even try it. You&amp;rsquo;ll just end up hating yourself. In fact, you might as well remove all your old custom Powerline fonts, they&amp;rsquo;re pretty much useless now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re on OSX or Windows, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Lokaltog/powerline-fonts&#34;&gt;download the new ones&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;re not all there yet unfortunately, but the good news is &lt;a href=&#34;http://lokaltog.github.com/powerline/fontpatching.html&#34;&gt;you can patch them yourself&lt;/a&gt; which I&amp;rsquo;m not even going to go into, you have fun with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re on Linux, you might be in luck, try &lt;a href=&#34;http://lokaltog.github.com/powerline/overview.html#linux&#34;&gt;this bit of the install guide&lt;/a&gt; and you might never have to patch your fonts again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuration:b588c49916508cfd3540e7ace30ddadd&#34;&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay that covers the install of the requirements (I think.. let me know if I missed one). The rest is pretty straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://lokaltog.github.com/powerline/&#34;&gt;official install guide&lt;/a&gt; will explain the rest to you, but I&amp;rsquo;ll put some of it here for posterity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;vim-1:b588c49916508cfd3540e7ace30ddadd&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You just need to drop this line into your .vimrc and you&amp;rsquo;ll be off to the races:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;python from powerline.ext.vim import source_plugin; source_plugin()
If you figured out where your Python has installed Powerline at, and you can&amp;rsquo;t get Python to work in Vim, you can use the absolute path like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-vim&#34;&gt;source {path}/powerline/ext/vim/source_plugin.vim
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;help-and-troubleshooting:b588c49916508cfd3540e7ace30ddadd&#34;&gt;Help and Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lokaltog.github.com/powerline/&#34;&gt;The official docs have different information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search the open AND closed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Lokaltog/powerline/issues&#34;&gt;github issues&lt;/a&gt;, seriously, there is loads of good advice there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore anything older than a month, since its probably about the old version of Powerline - and a completely different codebase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Google&amp;rsquo;s site search syntax like this: &lt;code&gt;site:https://github.com/Lokaltog/powerline/issues&lt;/code&gt; to search powerline&amp;rsquo;s github issues.. yes I&amp;rsquo;m saying this twice, it was a big help to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I never got the Python version of Powerline to work for Tmux yet (appears to be a bug in the weather widget).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cukeplusplus</title>
      <link>http://anthonymcook.com/cukeplusplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://anthonymcook.com/cukeplusplus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;aside class=&#34;url&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/acook/cukeplusplus&#34;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;github.com&lt;/div&gt;
cukeplusplus
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was dissatisfied with existing Cucumber formatters and spent a few
hours figuring out the API and dismantling the Pretty formatter in order
to create this. Cukeplusplus is inspired by the easy to read colorized
output of Emerge, Gentoo’s package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has no dependancies other than Cucumber itself, and I’m kind of in
love with how it looks on my terminal. Honestly the code is a mess, it
was written during a 32-hour coding session and my primary goal was
useful output in the fastest time possible. So I’ll do some code
cleanup, finish the Readme, and package it as a gem; then post some
screenshots and a screencast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone wants to help out or has some suggestions, feel free to throw
them my way, fork the code on Github and send me a pull request!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planned features: Show more detail about the running step and compile
statistics to catch particularly slow steps so we can optimize test
running time. I’d like to add more colors, but I’m kinda digging the way
it looks right now. I may add optional 256 color support, so I can use
more shades of grey and make sure people can see the same attractive
colors I see in my own terminal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;⦂∀&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your brain on vim</title>
      <link>http://anthonymcook.com/this-is-your-brain-on-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://anthonymcook.com/this-is-your-brain-on-vim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;aside class=&#34;url&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kevinw.github.com/2010/12/15/this-is-your-brain-on-vim&#34;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;kevinw.github.com&lt;/div&gt;
This is Your Brain on Vim
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its insanity. I love it. ⦂∀&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacVim vs iTerm</title>
      <link>http://anthonymcook.com/iterm2-vs-macvim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://anthonymcook.com/iterm2-vs-macvim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://40.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_ldk2dejdKO1qfucqto1_1280.png&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://40.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_ldk2dejdKO1qfucqto1_1280.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;⦂∀&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRB &amp; iTerm</title>
      <link>http://anthonymcook.com/an-iterm-bookmark-for-irb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://anthonymcook.com/an-iterm-bookmark-for-irb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/anthony_m_cook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;, you use &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactive_Ruby_Shell&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;irb&lt;/a&gt; for all kinds of things. From just running quick ruby experiments to figuring out how many &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubydoc.info/docs/ruby-core/1.9.2/Time&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;days&lt;/a&gt; (9364) you&amp;rsquo;ve been alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a bookmark in &lt;a href=&#34;http://iterm.sourceforge.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iTerm&lt;/a&gt; to run &lt;a href=&#34;http://ruby-doc.org/docs/ProgrammingRuby/html/irb.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;irb&lt;/a&gt; when I hit &lt;a href=&#34;http://jrgraphix.net/r/Unicode/2300-23FF&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;⌘&lt;/a&gt;-control-0. This was fine until I realized it was using the system&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3474875/why-does-mac-os-x-come-with-ruby-rails&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ruby&lt;/a&gt; install, and not the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubydoc.info/docs/ruby-core/1.9.2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;version&lt;/a&gt; I installed with &lt;a href=&#34;http://rvm.beginrescueend.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RVM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually realized the problem was the system environment doesn&amp;rsquo;t know about my &lt;a href=&#34;http://dotfiles.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;.bash_profile&lt;/a&gt;, and therefore my modified &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxheadquarters.com/howto/basic/path.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PATH&lt;/a&gt; variable nor the require &lt;a href=&#34;http://rvm.beginrescueend.com/rvm/install/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RVM magic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to get all that, this is the command to use to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re getting the same irb you expect from your commandline:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;bash --login -c irb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Yay it works!&lt;br/&gt;
⦂∀&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>