<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Startups on digital. [nomad]</title>
    <link>http://anthonymcook.com/tags/startups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Startups on digital. [nomad]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://anthonymcook.com/tags/startups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Lessons Learned&#34; by Devver</title>
      <link>http://anthonymcook.com/articles/learning-from-failing-startups-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://anthonymcook.com/articles/learning-from-failing-startups-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-from-failed-startups:5e125ae7b645ad66b943f5f13529d8c6&#34;&gt;Learning From Failed Startups&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;EDIT:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is excerpted from
&lt;a href=&#34; http://devver.wordpress.com/2010/04/26/lessons-learned &#34;&gt;Devver&#39;s blog&lt;/a&gt;
for posterity.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we were hesitant to ask for feedback and help. We quickly found that
people are incredibly helpful and generous with their time. Users were
willing to take a chance and use our products while giving us valuable
feedback. Fellow Rubyists gave us ideas and helped us with technical
problems. Mentors made time for meetings and introduced us to others who
could assist us. And other entrepreneurs, both new and seasoned, were
happy to share stories, compare experiences, and offer support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We embraced working remotely: we hired Avdi to work in Pennsylvania
while Dan and I lived in Boulder and later on, Dan moved to Washington,
DC. There are many benefits to having a distributed team, but two stood
out in our experience. First, we could hire top talent without having to
worry about location (in fact, our flexibility regarding location was
very attractive to most candidates we interviewed). Secondly, being in
different locations allowed every team member to work with minimal
distractions, which is invaluable when it comes to efficiently writing
good code.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
That said, communication was a challenge. To ensure we were all synced
up, we had a daily standup as well as a weekly review. When Dan moved to
DC, he and I scheduled another weekly meeting with no set agenda to just
bring up all the issues, large and small, that were on our minds. We
also all got together in the same location every few months to work in
the same room and rekindle our team energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Also, pair programming was difficult to do remotely and we never came up
with a great solution. As a result, we spent less than a day pairing a
week on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The most significant drawback to a remote team is the administrative
hassle. It’s a pain to manage payroll, unemployment, insurance, etc in
one state. It’s a freaking nightmare to manage in three states (well,
two states and a district), even though we paid a payroll service to
take care of it. Apparently, once your startup gets larger, there are
companies that will manage this with minimal hassle, but for a small
team, it was a major annoyance and distraction.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we should have focused more on customer development and finding a
minimum viable product (MVP)”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mistake at that point was to go “heads down” and focus on building
the accelerator while minimizing our contact with users and customers
(after all, we knew how great it was and time spent talking to customers
was time we could be hacking!). We should have asking, “Is there an even
simpler version of this product that we can deliver sooner to learn more
about pricing, market size, and technical challenges?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;url&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://devver.wordpress.com/2010/04/26/lessons-learned&#34;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;read the full post&lt;/div&gt;
Lessons Learned
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living in a Cave</title>
      <link>http://anthonymcook.com/articles/whatever-i-am-doing-a-lot-of-other-people-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://anthonymcook.com/articles/whatever-i-am-doing-a-lot-of-other-people-have/</guid>
      <description>&lt;aside class=&#34;url&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20120103005750/http://www.themomorohoax.com/2010/02/01/are-you-living-in-a-cave&#34;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;themomorohoax.com&lt;/div&gt;
Are you Living in a Cave?
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too many startup people act like they are sitting in a cave inventing
something utterly new.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Chances are, they’re not.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 I constantly find myself amazed when I recommend a blog post, or a
tactic to someone and they are like “Oh, that’s just what I need! I
never thought to search for that.” Even more amazing is when someone
labors day and night trying to figure out how to make a successful app
yet has never heard of something like a/b testing.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 I feel like these people must be living in caves.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 One of the fun parts of the University of Chicago was that we
constantly had to do research. This, plus being a programmer, entirely
convinced me of the following:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 “Whatever I am doing, a lot of other people have probably also tried
to do it. Some of them have probably been way more successful than I
have been so far. Some of them have probably written books or blog
posts about how they successfully did what I am doing now. I can find
these books and blog posts on Google and then apply what they say.”
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 The four sentences above are somehow not common knowledge, in my
experience. I have no idea why.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google, APIs, books, blogs, and most importantly &lt;em&gt;other people&lt;/em&gt; are my
external memory and processing units. We are all part of the same
beowulf cluster! Use the fantastic abilities of the other nodes around
you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;⦂∀&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>