<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cucumber on digital. [nomad]</title>
    <link>http://anthonymcook.com/tags/cucumber/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cucumber on digital. [nomad]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://anthonymcook.com/tags/cucumber/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cukeplusplus</title>
      <link>http://anthonymcook.com/cukeplusplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://anthonymcook.com/cukeplusplus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;aside class=&#34;url&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/acook/cukeplusplus&#34;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;github.com&lt;/div&gt;
cukeplusplus
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was dissatisfied with existing Cucumber formatters and spent a few
hours figuring out the API and dismantling the Pretty formatter in order
to create this. Cukeplusplus is inspired by the easy to read colorized
output of Emerge, Gentoo’s package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has no dependancies other than Cucumber itself, and I’m kind of in
love with how it looks on my terminal. Honestly the code is a mess, it
was written during a 32-hour coding session and my primary goal was
useful output in the fastest time possible. So I’ll do some code
cleanup, finish the Readme, and package it as a gem; then post some
screenshots and a screencast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone wants to help out or has some suggestions, feel free to throw
them my way, fork the code on Github and send me a pull request!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planned features: Show more detail about the running step and compile
statistics to catch particularly slow steps so we can optimize test
running time. I’d like to add more colors, but I’m kinda digging the way
it looks right now. I may add optional 256 color support, so I can use
more shades of grey and make sure people can see the same attractive
colors I see in my own terminal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;⦂∀&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>