<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Words Of Wisdom Not Invented Here Living In A Cave Startups on digital. [nomad]</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/words-of-wisdom-not-invented-here-living-in-a-cave-startups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Words Of Wisdom Not Invented Here Living In A Cave Startups on digital. [nomad]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/words-of-wisdom-not-invented-here-living-in-a-cave-startups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>“Whatever I am doing, a lot of other people have probably also tried to do it. Some of them have probably been way more successful than I have been so far. Some of them have probably written books or blog posts about how they successfully did what I am doing now. I can find these books and blog posts on Google and then apply what they say.”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/whatever-i-am-doing-a-lot-of-other-people-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/whatever-i-am-doing-a-lot-of-other-people-have/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.themomorohoax.com/2010/02/01/are-you-living-in-a-cave&#34;&gt;http://www.themomorohoax.com/2010/02/01/are-you-living-in-a-cave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too many startup people act like they are sitting in a cave inventing
something utterly new.\
\
 Chances are, they’re not.\
\
 I constantly find myself amazed when I recommend a blog post, or a
tactic to someone and they are like “Oh, that’s just what I need! I
never thought to search for that.” Even more amazing is when someone
labors day and night trying to figure out how to make a successful app
yet has never heard of something like a/b testing.\
\
 I feel like these people must be living in caves.\
\
 One of the fun parts of the University of Chicago was that we
constantly had to do research. This, plus being a programmer, entirely
convinced me of the following:\
\
 “Whatever I am doing, a lot of other people have probably also tried
to do it. Some of them have probably been way more successful than I
have been so far. Some of them have probably written books or blog
posts about how they successfully did what I am doing now. I can find
these books and blog posts on Google and then apply what they say.”\
\
 The four sentences above are somehow not common knowledge, in my
experience. I have no idea why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google, APIs, books, blogs, and most importantly &lt;em&gt;other people&lt;/em&gt; are my
external memory and processing units. We are all part of the same
beowulf cluster! Use the fantastic abilities of the other nodes around
you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;⦂∀&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>